Dagwon
다그온
Yuusha Shirei
용자지령
Brave Command Dagwon
라이 녀석… 자백시키고 말겠어!
Rai, that punk… I'll make him confess!
알았습니다. 해부하도록 하죠!
Got it. Let's dissect him!
켄타!
Kenta!
제길…!
Dammit!
라이… 이자식!
Rai! You bastard!
선배…
Senpai…
네놈의 목적이란 게 저런 꼬마애를 죽이는 거였냐?!
Your objective was to kill a child like him?
기, 기다려!
W- wait!
이게 극비 임무냐?! 정말 어이가 없다!
This is your secret mission? Secret your ass!
The Boy with Crystal Eyes
수정 눈동자 소년
Second Part
후편
대장!
Boss!
표적은 레벨 3으로 이행했다.
The target has evolved to Level 3.
더 이상 한시의 여유도 없어.
There is no more time to lose.
방심하지 마라.
Keep your guards up.
표적이 행동을 같이하고 있는 자들은…
Targets are acting with…
다그온이다!
Dagwon!
말살(抹殺)!
Erasure!
섀도우 곡괭이(鶴嘴)!
Shadow Pickaxe!
류!
Ryu!
5시 방향으로 40미터 떨어진 곳에 동굴이 있어.
There's a cave 5'o clock 40 meters away.
그렇군!
Right!
놓치지 않는다!
You're not running away!
그렇겐 안된다!
I won't let you do that!
트라이 다그온!
Try Dagwon!
이쪽이에요!
This way!
아무리 다그온이라 해도 결국은 아마추어 집단.
Even for Dagwon, you are bunch of amateurs.
우리 적수가 못 된다!
You are no match for us!
우리 집을 날려버린 건…
The one who made my house disappear…
라이였군…!
… is Rai?
나 참, 우주 경찰 기구도 갈 데까지 갔구만.
Man, I guess the Space Police Organization is on its last legs!
어린애 한 명에게 떼거지로 달려들다니…
An all-out attack to catch a kid, huh?
하지만 어째서 켄타 군을…?
But why would they do that to Kenta?
-당연하잖아.
-네?
-Isn't it obvious?
-Huh?
감쪽같이 변신했다고 생각했겠지만 난 못 속인다구.
He might think he transformed perfectly, but he's not fooling me!
정체를 드러내란 말이야, 이 우주인 녀석아!
Show your true identity, you damn alien!
켄타가 어딜 봐서 우주인이냐?!
What aspect of Kenta makes him an alien?!
맞아요! 어딜 봐도 인간이잖아요.
Right! He's definitely a human.
노, 농담이라구.
It was a joke…
게다가, 우주인이라고 쳐도 그다지 뭔 일을 한 건 아니잖아?
And even if he is an alien, he didn't really do a thing!
그러니까, 우주인이 아니라니까!
That's why I told you he's not an alien!
정말 불쌍하구만.
He's so pitiful.
불쌍해…
Pitiful…
라이 녀석… 이런 가냘픈 아이에게 총을 들이대다니!
Damn Rai… how can he even think about shooting this weak boy?
언어 도단(言語道斷)!
Outrageous!
옳으신 말씀.
True, true.
켄타.
Kenta.
반드시 내가 지켜줄게.
I'll protect you no matter what.
"내가"가 아니야!
It's not I!
"우리"다.
It's we.
그 말대로다! 나도 협력하마!
That's right! I'll help too!
표적을 놓쳤다고?
You lost the target?
네!
Yes!
그래…
I see.
대장!
Boss!
난…
I'll…
레벨 4에 대비하겠다.
… prepare for level 4.
류!
Ryu!
괜찮아?
Are you alright?
좀 긁혔을 뿐이야.
It's just a scratch.
-그래서…?
-적은 라이를 포함해서 9명이야.
-And?
-There's total of 9 enemies, including Rai.
머지않아 이곳도 발각될 거야.
They'll find out shortly.
도망칠 길은?
Where's the escape?
이 종유동은 학교 지하로 이어져 있어. 곧 이동하자.
This cave is connected to the ground floor of our school. Let's move soon.
다그 롬보스포 기동!
Dag Lombus Cannon - Activate!
젠장…!
Dammit!
도망치기만 해선 끝나질 않아.
Running away won't get us anywhere!
맞는 말이야.
Right!
아무래도 우리도 변신할 필요가 있겠군.
It seems that we will have to be able to transform too.
지금부터 각자 자택에 보관되어 있는 다그 커맨더를 회수하러 간다!
To each his own, you will go home to retrieve your Dag Commanders!
오우, 그게 좋겠구만!
Right! Good idea!
그 수밖에 없겠군요.
Seems that we'll have to.
커맨더 말이지…
The Commander, eh?
왜 그래, 신?
What's wrong, Shin?
아니, 어디다 뒀더라…
I wonder where I put that…
설마 신성한 다그 커맨더를…?!
You lost your divine Dag Commander?!
어쩔 수 없잖아! 이렇게 될 거라고 누가 알았겠냐?
Like I knew things like this would happen!
어쨌든 서두릅시다.
Anyway, let's hurry.
조심해라 녀석들은 실력자야.
Be careful. They are skilled.
하지만 마을 안에선 습격하지 않을 거야.
But they won't attack in the city.
그래 그 녀석들, 사람들 눈에 띄는 건 피하는 모양이니까.
Right. They seemed to avoid being seen by people.
좋아, 행동 개시다!
Alright. Let's begin the operation!
다그 커맨더를 회수하면 이 제 9 연구실에서 다시 한번 합류한다.
When you retrieve your Dag Commander, gather in the 9th laboratory again.
건투를 빈다!
Good luck!
"건투를 빈다"라…
Good luck, huh?
우리 집이 안 없어졌다면 나도…
If my house didn't disappear, I'd also…
너나 나나 집없는 신세구나.
We're both homeless, I guess.
엄마 돌아오시면 놀라 뒤집어지시겠구만.
When my parents come back, they'll freaked out!
그건 그렇고, 미나코는?
By the way, how's Minako doing?
그녀석이라면 걱정 없어.
Don't worry about her.
그렇구만. 류의 여동생이니까…
I see. She's your younger sister after all!!
1교시가 체육이었던가.
Is the first class P. E.?
-수업 들어갈까?
-바보같은 소리 마라!
-Want to attend it?
-Don't say such a stupid thing!
지금이 학교 갈 때냐! 그치, 켄타?
This is not the time to go to school! Right, Kenta?
-학교…
-너, 학교 안 다녔어?
-School…
-Didn't you attend school?
부럽다고 할지 뭐라 할지…
I don't know if I envy you or not…
그치만 말이야 나름대로 즐겁다구.
But still, it's fun unlike how it looks.
-즐거워…
-그래!
-Fun…
-Yeah!
공부는 싫지만 말이야, 학원제라든가 수학여행이라든가 다양한 행사가 있어서 말이야.
I hate studying, but there are various events like festivals or trips!
행사…
Events…
게다가, 무엇보다 친구가 생긴다는 점이 좋지.
Moreover, what's good is that we get friends!
친구…
Friends?
그래!
Yeah!
이녀석도 말이지.
Like him.
그리고, 좀전의 녀석들도 모두 학교에서 알게 된 친구야.
Those guys just before are also friends that I made in school.
학교… 친구…
School… Friends…
물론 너도 말이야.
Of course, including you.
잘 부탁한다, 켄타.
Nice to meet you, Kenta.
류… 엔…
Ryu… En…
친구… 불쌍해…
Friends… pitiful…
커맨더 커맨더 커맨더~
Commander~ Commander~ Commander~
있다!
Here!
아이구야…
Ouch…
트라이 다그…
Try Dag-
그 아이는 어디 있나?
Where is that boy?!
대답해라!
Answer me!
-게키!
-무사하냐, 요쿠?
-Geki!
-Are you alright, Yoku?
라이 녀석… 학교로 향할 셈이야!
Damn Rai… He's heading to the school!
그 전에 붙잡아 주마!
We'll get you before that happens!
싸움 시작됐어.
The battle has begun.
실력 행사에 나섰군.
They're using force.
왜 그래?
What's wrong?
까먹고 있었어! 내 다그 커맨더 있어!
I forgot! I have my Dag Commander!
뭐?
Huh?
켄타! 곧 돌아올 테니까 여기서 기다려.
Kenta! I'll be back soon, so wait here!
안돼!
No!
엔… 친구… 그러니까 안돼…
En… friend… so I can't!
그래, 친구야. 넌 누구에게도 넘겨주지 않아. 알았지?
Yes, I am your friend. I will never hand you to anybody else. Understood?
류!
Ryu!
켄타를 부탁해.
Take care of Kenta!
엔!
En!
어서…
Hurry…
켄타가 있는 곳으로…!
To where Kenta is!
크리스탈 부메랑!
Crystal Boomerang!
이른 아침부터 누구야?
Who is it, this early in the morning?
엔, 무슨 일이야?
En, what's up?
내 다그 커맨더, 돌려줘.
Give me back my Dag Commander.
뭐? 나한테 줬잖아. 지금와서 그런 게 어딨어.
Huh? Didn't you give it to me? You're too late for that!
전당포에 맡겨야 돼.
I'm handing it to a pawnshop.
전당포?
Pawnshop?
마리아에게 꾼 돈 갚아야 돼.
I have to pay back the debt to Maria.
어머?
Huh?
요즘 돈 꾼게 있었던가?
Did you borrow any money recently?
마리아…
Maria.
그때 이후로 어디에 갔었어?
Where did you go since then?
그냥 뭐…
Well…
그 켄타란 애 말인데…
That Kenta…
너 낯익지 않았어?
Doesn't he look familiar?
나, 알았어.
I think I got this.
자, 봐.
Look.
8년 전 사진이야.
A picture taken 8 years ago.
봐, 그 애, 옛날 너와 똑같이 생겼어.
That kid looks just like him with you from the past!
그런가? 안 닮았어.
Is that so? They don't look alike!
엔!
En!
받아!
Here you go!
나중에 보자.
See ya!
너무 무리하지마.
Don't overdo it!
알았어.
Sure!
엔, 죽지마…
En, please don't die…
켄타, 절대 여기서 나가지마!
Kenta, absolutely never leave here!
류!
Ryu!
트라이 다그온.
Try Dagwon!
저건, 라이?!
That must be Rai!
켄타, 어딨어?!
Kenta! Where are you?!
뭘 그리 멍하니 걷고 있니? 위험하잖니.
Watch where you're going! That was dangerous!
너, 초등학생이지? 학교 빠져도 괜찮니?
Are you an elementary school student? Are you skipping school?
-학교…
-뭐, 좋아.
-School…
-Anyway!
그 자유로운 정신은 칭찬해 줄게.
I praise your free spirit!
학교… 친구… 불쌍해…
School… friends… pitiful…
어머, 다쳤잖아! 어서 병원에 가야지.
Hey, you're injured! Let's go to a hospital.
켄타, 내가 아는 사람이랑 조금 닮았구나.
Kenta, you look like someone I know.
뭐, 네 쪽이 조금 더 좋은 남자지만 말이야.
Well, at least you're better man than him.
저기, 치료가 끝나면 데이트 할까?
Hey, would you like to go on a date after the hospital?
-데이트…
-그래.
-Date…
-Right.
오락실에 가고 노래방에 가고 그리고 밥 먹으러 가자.
Let's go play in an arcade, sing in a karaoke, and eat in a restaurant!
먹어…
Eat…
사양하지 않아도 괜찮아 우린 이제 친구잖아.
You don't have to refuse! We're friends now.
친구…
Friends…
친구, 죽이고 싶지 않아!
Friends, I do not want to kill.
켄타!
Kenta!
대장!
Boss!
켄타!
Kenta!
-인정사정 없구만, 라이!
-엔…
-You're really merciless, Rai
-En…
젠장!
Dammit!
왜 그곳에서 나간 거야?
Why did you get out of there?
엔, 죽이고 싶지 않아.
En, I do not want to kill.
내가 그렇게 쉽게 당할 리…
There's no way I'm that easily…
없잖아?!
… killed!
저리 꺼져!
Get lost!
-오래 기다렸지?
-왜이리 늦어!
-Sorry to keep you waiting!
-You're late!
다그 커맨더를 타인에게 넘기다니! 이런 바보같은 녀석!
How dare you hand your Dag Commander over to someone else?! You damn idiot!
쓸데없는 참견마!
You're being noisy!
엔, 켄타를 데리고 도망쳐라!
En! Take Kenta and run away!
순순히 불어라 어째서 그 아이를 노리는 거지?
Tell us. Why are you after that boy?!
선배…
Senpai…
날 괴롭게 하지 마라!
Do not make me hurt you!
엔, 내려줘.
En, put me down.
-뭐?
-엔, 도망쳐!
-What?!
-En, run away!
걱정해 주는 거냐? 고맙다.
Are you worrying about me? Thank you.
그래, 가 볼까? 애들 다 불러서 말이야.
Oh, right! Let's go! With everyone else!
바다에 데려가 줄게!
I'll take you! To the sea!
켄타가 지구를 멸망시킨다고?!
Kenta will bring ruin to the Earth?!
그 생물의 이름은 데안도조르 "불모의 대지"를 뜻하는 말입니다.
The name of that creature is Deandozol, meaning barren earth.
지구를 멸망시킨다는 건 무슨 의미지?
What does it mean to bring ruin to the Earth?!
녀석들은 우주 공간에 씨앗을 날립니다.
They let their seeds fly into Space.
어느 별에 떨어진 씨앗은 성장하여 그 별의 모든 생체 에너지를 빨아들이면 다시 새로운 씨앗을 날립니다.
When a seed falls onto a planet, it grows by soaking the life energy of that planet, and when it's done, it spreads again.
그래서 지금까지 수많은 혹성이 사멸해 왔습니다.
Because of that, numerous planets were destroyed up until now!
어째서 그걸 더 빨리 말하지 않은 거야?!
Why didn't you hurry up and tell us that earlier?!
말씀드리면 협력해 주셨을 겁니까?
If I told you, would you have helped us?
녀석을 그 손으로 죽여주셨을 겁니까?!
Would you have killed him by your own hands?!
왜이리 끈질겨!
Persistent bastards!
엔, 도망쳐!
En, run away!
날 믿어!
Believe in me.
엔!
En!
왜그래, 켄타?!
What's wrong, Kenta?!
안돼!
No!
켄타!
Kenta!
설마, 켄타 군은…
Was Kenta actually…
나…
I…
저곳에 떨어졌어야 했어.
… should have fell there.
켄타!
Kenta!
류!
Ryu!
그곳에서 떨어지세요!
Move away!
늦었어…
We were too late…
레벨 4로 이행하고 말았어.
It evolved to level 4…
레벨 4?
Level 4?
더 이상 우리 장비로는 없앨 수 없습니다.
We cannot eliminate it with our devices anymore.
없앤다고?
Eliminate?
켄타는… 말이야.
Kenta is…
켄타는…
-거짓말이야!
-거짓말이 아닙니다.
-It's a lie!
-It's not a lie!
녀석은 우주 해충입니다.
That guy is a harmful insect of space.
해, 해충?
I- insect?!
녀석은 머지않아 레벨 5로 이행할 겁니다.
It will soon evolve to level 5.
그렇게 되면…
When that happens…
-지구는 멸망합니다!
-멸망이라고?!
-The Earth will perish!
-Perish?!
전 위성으로 돌아가 위성 병기를 사용하겠습니다.
I will go back to the satellite, and use the satellite weapon.
위성 병기?
Satellite weapon?
산카이 시와 그 주변 도시도 소멸하겠지만 남은 방법은 그것 밖에 없습니다.
Sankai and its surrounding cities will disappear too, but we have no other option.
-그에 따라, 전…
-할 수 있겠냐?
-So, I'll…
-Can you do this?
네가 우리를 쏠 수 있겠냔 말이다!
Can you shoot us?
그게 제 임무입니다!
That is my mission!
작별입니다, 선배들.
Farewell, senpais.
되도록 먼 곳으로 피난해 주십시오.
Please escape to a place far away.
들었지? 모두 어서 도망쳐.
Did you hear? Everyone, hurry and escape.
그럴 순 없지.
I cannot do that.
난 명예 풍기 위원장이다.
I am the honorary chief of discipline.
카이…
Kai…
나도 함께 있을래 어차피 데이트도 파투났으니.
I'll stay too. My date was canceled after all.
나도 아르바이트 쉴래.
I'll drop the shift for my job too.
게다가, 레벨 5가 어떤 모습인지 보고 싶어요.
Also, I want to see how its level 5 looks!
넌 정말 변함이 없구만.
You really never change, huh?
너희들…!
Everyone!
에너지 충전 완료.
Energy charge complete.
-목표 포착.
-조준 안정 OK.
-Target set.
-Aim stabilization ready.
-언제든지 발사할 수 있습니다.
-대장, 발사 버튼을!
-We can fire at anytime.
-Boss, press the shoot button!
레벨 5로 이행된다면 다그 롬보스포로 말살하는 것조차 불가능해집니다.
When it evolves to level 5, killing it with the Dag Lombus Cannon will be impossible!
알고 있어.
I know.
-하지만, 정말 믿겨지질 않는구만.
-어딜 봐도 인간이었는데 말이야.
-But still I can't believe this.
-It surely looked like a human.
-의태(擬態)라는 거래.
-의태?
-It's mimicry.
-Mimicry?
곤충이 나뭇잎이나 가지로 가장하는 것 말이죠?
By that, you mean a bug disguising as a leaf or branch, right?
데안도조르의 씨앗은 어느 별에 떨어지면 그 별에서 최초로 본 생물로 의태하는 것 같아.
It seems that the seed of Deandozol performs the mimicry of the first creature it sees when it lands on a planet.
아무도 찾을 수 없는 곳에서 8년간의 세월을 보내면.
If it spent 8 years in a place that nobody can find…
8년?!
8 years?!
8년 전의 사진.
A picture taken 8 years ago.
그 애, 옛날 너와 똑같이 생겼어.
That kid looks just like him with you from the past!
켄타!
Kenta!
어이! 기다려!
Hey, wait, Kenta!
왜 그래, 켄타?
What's wrong, Kenta?
그런…
No way…
그런 일이…!
How can it be?!
켄타가 8년 전의 엔이었다니…
Kenta is En from 8 years ago.
어쩐지 한방 쥐어박고 싶더라.
That's why I wanted to hit him hard!
켄타…
Kenta…
이건…?
This is…
레벨 5?!
Level 5?!
라이…!
Rai…
누르지 못했습니다…
I couldn't press it.
선배들을 향해…
Aiming at my senpais…
전 버튼을 누르지 못했습니다…!
I couldn't press the button!
그럼…?
So then…
이미 혹성 파괴 부대가 움직이기 시작했습니다.
The planet destruction unit has already started to move.
이제 지구를 구할 방법은 없습니다!
There is no way to save the Earth anymore!
우리 모두…
All of us…
다그온 실격이란 말이군.
… are disqualified as Dagwons.
저건 뭐지?
What's that?
데안도조르는 우선 자기 주위에 에너지 필드를 형성합니다.
As its first step, Deandozol creates an energy field around itself.
이곳에서 떨어집시다. 필드 내에서 무슨 일이 벌어질지는 일체 불명입니다.
Let's get away from here. There is nothing known about what's going on inside the field.
선배, 어서 탈출하지 않으면…
Senpai, if we don't escape quickly…
미안해. 마지막까지 지켜보게 해줘.
Sorry. Let us watch to the end.
하느님 말이야.
Will there…
있을까?
… be a god?
난 없을 거라고 생각해.
I think it doesn't exist.
그치만, 그렇잖아.
Look at this.
만약 있다면…
If there was one…
이런 가혹한 짓을 할 리 없어.
… it would never do something this cruel.
엔…
En…
켄타!
Kenta!
켄타야?!
Is that Kenta?
엔…
En…
미유키가 말했어.
Miyuki told me.
미유키가?
Miyuki?
엔이랑 미유키랑 나랑… 3명은 형제라고…
That En, Miyuki, and me… The three of us are brothers.
우리가 형제?
We are brothers?
게다가…
Moreover…
카이도 신도 요쿠도 류도 게키도 라이도.
Kai, Shin, Yoku, Ryu, Geki, and Rai too…
모두 엔의 소중한 친구라고.
… are En's dearest friends.
그러니까 부탁을 들어주지 않을래?
So, will you respond to my request?
부탁?
Request?
너희들의 힘으로 날…
With your powers, take me…
이 에너지 필드 안쪽이라면 할 수 있어.
In this energy field, you'll be able to.
카이도 신도 요쿠도 류도 게키도 라이도.
This is…
모두 엔의 소중한 친구라고.
Kenta, you…!
그러니까 부탁을 들어주지 않을래?
Must we…
부탁?
Must we do this?
부탁해… 날…
Please. Take me…
부탁이야, 엔!
Please, En!
엔… 형…
En… brother…
켄타!
Kenta!
-말도 안돼, 있을 수 없어!
-데안도조르의 에너지 반응이 사라졌어!
-Deandozol's energy reaction has disappeared.
-No way! It's impossible!
歩道橋の上 君が手を振った
hodoukyou no ue kimi ga te futta
High above the overpass, you waved your hand
육교 위에서 네가 손을 흔들었지
hodoukyou no ue kimi ga te wo futta
インディゴのシャツが 空と交わる
INDIGO no SHATSU ga sora wo majiwaru
Indigo shirts cross with the sky
남색 셔츠가 하늘과 교차해
INDIGO no SHATSU ga sora wo majiwaru
約束通りに 僕はこうやって
yakusoku doori ni boku wa kouyatte
As promised, I am like this
약속대로 난 이렇게
yakusoku doori ni boku wa kouyatte
笑顔に着がえて 見送るのさ
egao ni kigaete miokuru no sa
Sending for you after changing to a smiling face
웃는 얼굴로 갈아입고 배웅하고 있어
egao ni kigaete miokuru no sa
望むままに 君は 羽ばたいてく
nozomu mama ni kimi wa habataiteku
Go and leave your hopes on flapping wings
바라는 대로 넌 날개치며 떠나가네
nozomu mama ni kimi wa habataiteku
自由な心を 誇りに思うよ
jiyuu na kokoro wo hokori ni omou yo
Be proud of your free soul
자유로운 마음을 자랑으로 여겨
jiyuu na kokoro wo hokori ni omou yo
もしも辛く なった日は
moshi mo tsuraku natta hi wa
On a day when you became painful
만약 힘들어지는 날엔
moshimo tsuraku natta hi wa
黙って目を 閉じるんだ
damatte me wo tojirunda
I silently close my eyes
조용히 눈을 감아
damatte me wo tojirunda
ときめく気持ちが よみがえるはず
tokimeku kimochi ga yomigaeru hazu
Your fluttering feelings will be revived
설레는 마음이 되살아날 거야
tokimeku kimochi ga yomigaeru hazu
ひとつひとつ
hitotsu hitotsu
One by one
하나하나
hitotsu hitotsu
僕たちが 描いてきた 想い出は
bokutachi ga egaite kita omoide wa
The memories we drew…
우리가 그려온 추억은
bokutachi ga egaite kita omoide wa
語りかけるだろう 確かにそして
katari kakeru darou tashika ni soshite
…will be talked about, definitely and…
이야기할 수 있겠지, 확실히 그리고
katari kakeru darou tashika ni soshite
永遠に…
eien ni…
forever…
영원히…
eien ni…
Original Korean Subtitles by Jaebari (재바리)
Translated to English by Subdivers
Checked by Great Exkaiser103
자막 원본: 재바리
수정: Subdivers